Practical Methods for Estimating Defect Opportunities
Welcome to this session on defect opportunities.
What we have in front of us is a simple concept called defects per opportunity.
That's located out here in the far right-hand column.
That's our defects per opportunity. So, I’ll label that
defects per opportunity.
Now, along here in the numerator position, we have defects.
And in the denominator position, we have opportunities.
So, the numerator contains the defects
and the denominator contains the opportunities.
Now with that, what we’re looking at is each occurrence of a defect opportunity.
So this example, is for a certain CTQ,
CTQ dash eighteen, just for the sake of argument.
It’s just going to be known as CTQ 18.
Make our discussion easy.
Now given that, let's take a look at this block right here, that I’m now changing the color on.
To a fairly loud color there.
That one says, that opportunity was brought into existence.
That's what a one signifies, the opportunity was brought into existence.
Now if in fact, it had not been brought into existence, then a zero goes there.
Let's suppose the process cycle started, but was not completed, therefore a zero goes there.
So, what we’re talking about here, is the process cycle.
And I’m going to make that simple for us.
We’ll represent a cycle by the letter C.
And we’ll say that this is cycle 1, 2, 3,
4. Cycle 1, 2, 3, 4 of the process.
Where the outcome either completed the cycle or it did not. Zero did not complete the cycle.
Therefore, if I have a zero in the denominator for any given cycle.
It's impossible to have a one here. That would have to be zero.
Cause you see, if it didn't cycle, it didn't create a product.
If it didn't create a product, it could not have a defect. Therefore, a zero has to go there.
Simple way to think about it. Now, in this case,
let's suppose, notice I arrange the scenario.
Let's suppose that we cycled the process four times.
And of those four times, we had two successful cycles. Something was produced.
Of those two successful cycles,
cycle 2 and cycle 3, one had a defect.
Therefore, we produced
one defect out of two opportunities, or my defects per opportunity is .50.
That's an easy way to say that. Easy way to look at that.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.